Finding aid for the Noel Black Papers LSC.2320
UCLA Library Special Collections
Noel Black papers
1967-1990, bulk 1972-1990
1972-1990
UCLA Library Special Collections
Black, Noel
LSC.2320
3 Linear Feet (3 cartons)
The collection consists of scripts and production material related to the career of motion picture and television director Noel Black. Among the projects represented are Deadly Intentions, The Electric Grandma, Pretty Poison, and Promises to Keep, among others.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Marco Black, 2015.
General
UCLA Catalog Record ID:9980918203606533
Biography/History
Noel Anthony Black was born June 30, 1937, in Chicago, IL. Black earned both a B.A. and an M.A. in film studies from the University of California, Los Angeles. His short film, Skaterdater, was nominated for an Academy Award in 1966 and won the Palme d'Or for best short film at the Cannes Film Festival the same year. The short film drew the attention of Twentieth Century Fox, who chose him to direct the film, Pretty Poison (1968). Additional film credits include Cover Me Babe (1970), Jennifer on My Mind (1971), A Man, a Woman and a Bank (1979), Private School (1983) and Mischief (1985). Black also wrote and directed television shows such as Kojak and Quincy, M.E. in the mid-1970s. Additional television credits include I'm a Fool for the PBS series The American Short Story (1977), A Man, a Woman and a Bank (1979), The Electric Grandmother (1982), and Promises to Keep (1985), among others. Black retired in the early 1990s. He died July 5, 2014 in Santa Barbara, California.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of material related to the career of television and motion picture director Noel Black. Included are scripts and production information for motion picture and television projects. Among the motion picture projects represented are A Man, a Woman, and a Bank, Mischief, and Pretty Poison. Television projects include Deadly Intentions, The Electric Grandma, Promises to Keep and The Twilight Zone (1980s revival), among others.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Motion Picture Projects
Television Projects
Unidentifed Projects
Television producers and directors -- Archives; Motion picture producers and directors -- Archives; Black, Noel
- Motion Picture Projects
  Scope and Content
  This series contains scripts and/or production information for motion picture projects such as A Change of Seasons, A Man, a Woman, and a Bank, Marianne, Mischief, and Pretty Poison.
  Organization and Arrangement
  The series is arranged alphabetically by project title.
  - Casting Suggestions for: A Man, a Woman, and a Bank; Mirrors; Killer; and The Adventures of Auggie March, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - A Change of Seasons - clippings, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - A Change of Seasons - corrections, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - A Change of Seasons - production information and holographic notes, 1979 Nov -1980 Mar (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - A Change of Seasons - schedules and reports, 1980 Jan (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - A Change of Seasons - script, 1980 Jan 12 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - A Change of Seasons - references/memos, 1979 Dec - 1980 Feb (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Consenting Adults - script (aka A Change of Seasons), undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Good Boys, Nice Girls ([aka Mischief?]) - production information and correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Man, A Woman, and a Bank (A) - scripts and release form, undated (Box 1, Folder 21 and 22)
  - Marianne - scripts, 1974 Apr 30 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - Mischief (aka Heart and Soul) - scripts, 1984 May 7 (Box 3, Folder 10, 11, 12, 14, 15)
  - Mischief - budget information, 1985 March (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Mischief (aka Heart and Soul), 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Mischief (aka Heart and Soul) - activity reports, 1985 Feb 7 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Mischief (aka Heart and Soul) - casting information, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Mischief (aka Heart and Soul) - music notes, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Mischief (aka Heart and Soul) - production information and clippings, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Mischief (aka Heart and Soul) - production material, clippings, correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Mischief (aka Heart and Soul) - research, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - She Let Him Continue (released as Pretty Poison) - script, undated (Box 1, Folder 12 and 13)
- Television Projects
  The series contains scripts and/or production information for projects such as television movies, The Electric Grandma and Quarterback Princess; the television mini-series Deadly Intentions; and the television series The Twilight Zone (1980s), among others.
  - Conspiracy of Love - production information, 1987 May - Jul (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Conspiracy of Love - script, 1987 May 23 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Conspiracy of Love (MOW) [location photographs], undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Deadly Intentions- bound photocopy of book, undated (Box 3, Folder 5 and 6)
  - Deadly Intentions - broadcast standards and practices memos, 1984 Nov (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Deadly Intentions - production material and copies of clippings (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Deadly Intentions (aka Obsessed to Kill) - production information, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Deadly Intentions -final revised script, 1985 Jan 21 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Doctors Wilde (pilot) - scripts and production information, 1987 Feb 27 (Box 2, Folder 12 and 13)
  - Dolphin Bay: The Initiation of Lisa Ruddick - script and productio information, 1988 Dec 27 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Dolphin Bay: episode #1, 1988 Aug - Sep (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Electric Grandma (The) - script and production information, 1981 Jan (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Happy Endings - script and production information, 1982 Feb-Marc (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Hollow Boy (The) - correspondence, 1990 May - Aug (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Hollow Boy (The) - production information, contract, holographic notes, 1990 Jul - Sep (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Meet at the Munceys - production information, 1987 Dec (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Meet at the Munceys- script, 1987 Dec (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Nightmare Classics: The Eyes of the Panther - production information, 1989 Jan - Feb (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Nightmare Classics: The Eyes of the Panther - second draft script, 1989 Feb 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Obsessed to Kill (aka Deadly Intentions) - daily production reports, 1985 Jan - March (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Other Victim (The) - script and production information, 1981 Jun (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Prime Suspect (aka Cry of Innocence) - script, 1981 Apr (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Prme Suspect (aka Cry of Innocence) - script and production information, 1981 Apr - Oct (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Promises to Keep - script and production information, 1985 May-Aug (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Quarterback Princess - production information, 1983 Aug-Nov (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Quarterback Princess - script, 1983 Jul 21 (Box 1, Folder 10 and 11)
  - Time to Triumph - headshots and polaroids, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Time to Triumph - script and production information, 1985 Sep - Oct (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Twilight Zone: Song of the Younger World - script, 1986 Oct 1 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Twilight Zone: To See the Invisible Man - script, 1985 Dec 5 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Two Loves - scripts and production information, 1986 Jan-Feb (Box 1, Folder 7 and 8)
- Unidentified Projects
  - Holographic notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - TV Guide: Columbus on the Couch cover, 1985 May 18-24 (Box 3, Folder 1)